

# **Curriculum Vitae**

Name: Cuong Nguyen / Viet Cuong Nguyen

Address: Kieler Straße 395 22525, Hamburg, Germany

**E-Mail:** cuong.nguyen.viet2991@gmail.com

Phone: +49 15203957579

#### **About me:**

 Have experience in object-oriented programming, functional programming, and web development. Good programming knowledge and open and joy to quickly get used to new technologies

- Affinity with architectures, micro-services
- Advocate of Clean Code
- Successful working in both team and self-directed settings
- Fluent English and basic German

## **Education:**

Jun 2012 - Jan 2015 RMIT University Vietnam

Bachelor of Information Technology Major - Application Programming

GPA 3.63 / 4.00 (Australian grade scale)

Oct 2015 - Oct 2019 UHH - Universität Hamburg

MSc. Intelligent Adaptive System **GPA 1.88 / 1.00** (German grade scale)

#### **Work Experience / Internship:**

Oct 2014 - Jan 2015 CSC Viet Nam, Exceed J project

Associate Java Developer

- Front-end developer for an enterprise web application
- Technology: JavaEE, JavaServer Faces, PrimeFaces, jQuery
- Responsible for new front-end feature implementation, as well as testing and bug fixing
- Performance optimization using AJAX Dynatrace able to achieve great improvement on loading and processing time by reducing 3-5s on each individual operations

Feb 2020 - Dec 2020 data42 Gmbh, GOOSE project

Web Developer, Full-stack

Full-stack developer for the GOOSE project (single-page application) at data42

- Technology: functional programming, Clojure / Clojurescript, micro-services, AWS, CI/CD
- Responsible for new feature data visualization as graph, xml validation and improving error notification
- Support in the requirement, conception, and implementation of products and solutions

# **Course Completed:**

Oct 2013 - Dec 2013 Software Engineering - Process & Tools

Team Leader

- Designed and built a *Restaurant Point-Of-Sale System* in a team of 5 using Java, Swing and Agile development method
- Organized and facilitated daily reports, task distributions as well as weekly meetings with clients as Team Leader
- Paired-programming with team members
- Recommended for commercialization of the final product
- Chosen as showcase at University Open Day

Oct 2017 - Mar 2018 Human-Robot Interaction Master Project

**Team Member** 

- Team member of a group of 8 students working with a humanoid robot (NICO).
- Responsible for the vision module of the robot enable the robot to identify object and localization of object
- Co-author of the publication "Designing a Personality-Driven Robot for a Human-Robot Interaction Scenario". International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 2019.

Mar 2019 - Sep 2019 Master Thesis

- "Reinforcement Learning as Strategy for Engaging Task-oriented Dialogue Systems".
- Using Reinforcement Learning to interweave contents of a task-oriented and a chit-chat dialogue system.

## **Skills:**

Language: English - IELTS 8.0

German - Goethe-Zertifikat B1

Technology: Python, Java, Clojure, Html, Javascript, CSS

AJAX, Rest, Graphql, Node.js, Express, Vue.js

SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Object-Oriented Programming, Functional Programming

Software Engineering / Software Architecture

Data processing, data analyst, data visualization, ML

GitHub: franknvc.github.io